Nibil M S

Email: me@nibil.in / msnibil@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-9495 41 2790

skype : sayyidnibil

Summary

I'm a Techno-Functional professional who started my career as the first employee of a startup. I started off as a Development Engineer, later on transitioning myself to a managerial role in the second-tier leadership of the company while continuing my role as a Product Engineer in the company. In my 5-year stint with the startup, the company grew from 5 to 72 people. I have had the opportunity to experience the initial hiccups, the effective bootstrapping, external investment, acquisition and the growth of the company from multiple roles and perspectives.

I then associated with some companies as a consultant in both service and product background and has worked with clients across the world. I am now looking for exciting challenges where I can put my tech + management skills.

Work Experience

VP of Operations (Feb 2018 to Present)

Leadlytics Data Labs, Kerala (www.leadlyticslabs.com)

- Interact with clients to understand their needs
- Define the process for every client to make sure their expectations are met
- Help the HR team in the recruitment
- Lead the onboarding process.
- Lead the D2D operations
- Defined the architecture and lead the development of the internal Django web app
- Python language scripting.

Consultant (December 2016 to May 2018)

PropsAMC, Karnataka (<u>www.propsamc.com</u>)

(January 2018 - May 2018)

- Lead the product team and report to the CTO.
- Do the research and check the feasibility of the features.
- Define the features and software architecture of the product's version 2.0
- Lead the development and do the backend revamp using Django and VueJS
- Do code reviews and appraisals of developers

Vogo Automotive, Karnataka (<u>www.vogo.in</u>)

(April 2017 - November 2017)

- Lead the product team and report to the CTO.
- Do the research and check the feasibility of the features.
- Define the features and software architecture of the product's version 2.0
- Lead the development and do the backend revamp using the Django Rest Framework.
- Do code reviews and appraisals of developers

RawData Technologies, Kerala (<u>www.rawdatatech.com</u>) (November 2016 - March 2017)

- Reporting directly to the CEO, responsible in the handling service project WinWinUSA
- Interact with client to understand requirements, check feasibility & provide best suitable estimation accordingly.
- Deeply involved in recruiting developers into the team.
- Do code reviews and appraisals of developers

VP of Data Research (July 2014 to August 2016)

Profoundis Labs, Kerala

- Profoundis developed their flagship product (https://vibeapp.co) backed by a Human + Technology Hybrid engine which has been acquired by FullContact (https://fullcontact.com).
- As there was a need to grow Data Research as a function in the company, I gradually transitioned into a business role with client interactions.
- Directly reporting to Co-founder & Chief of Data Research, I led the operations side of data research function with the whole Data Research Team functionally reporting to me.
- Was also involved deeply in the recruitment, onboarding, training, performance appraisals as the team grew from 10 to 72.
- Part of the team that developed and maintained the internal Django web app that augmented the Data Research process.
- Python language scripting.

Senior Product Engineer (July 2012 to June 2014)

Profoundis Labs Private Ltd, Kerala (www.profoundis.com)

- Joined Profoundis as the first employee after the first month of the company's inception.
- Reporting directly to the CTO of the company; responsible for the services side of Profoundis which was then bootstrapping.
- Worked with clients from Turkey, the Middle East and the US including the likes of Vodafone which cumulatively earned over 100,000\$ for the company.
- Mostly worked with Python, Django, HTML and Javascript during this tenure.

Django Developer (August 2011 to June 2012)

As a prodigy of Mr Kenneth Gonsalves (Chairman, Indian Python Software Society, 2010 2011)

- Worked on multiple projects including the development and maintenance of Websites and Web applications in Python/Django.
- Clients included FIDA Kids (an NGO based out of Africa and India), Bamboo Banks (Ooty based hotel) and Ooty Golf Course.

Education

• Master of Business Administration in Project Management

Bharathiar University, Coimbatore (Pursuing)

• Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering

Kalinga University, Raipur

• Bachelor of Computer Application

Madurai Kamaraj University, Madurai

• Higher Secondary Examination

Govt Higher Secondary School, Kumaranellur

• Technical High School Leaving Certificate

Technical Higher Secondary School, Vattamkulam

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages and Frameworks:
 - Python, Django, Django Rest Framework
- Databases
 - PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Elasticsearch, MongoDB
- Operating Systems
 - GNU/Linux: both Redhat & Debian, Mac OS X, All Microsoft Windows Environments.
 - Bash scripting

Management Skills

- Business sense with a technology background.
- Leadership, Interpersonal and team skills
- Initiating, leading and optimizing day to day operations of a team at scale.
- Recruiting and building a team

Personal Information

Name : Nibil M S Sex : Male

Address : Needam, Trithala P.O, Palakkad-679534, Kerala, IN

Date of Birth : 06-10-1989 Marital Status : Married

Passport : Indian (#K3080682) Languages Known : English, Malayalam, Tamil